# **Matthew Carr**

https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthewcarr0317/

#### **SUMMARY**

As Senior Front-End Developer with over 7 years of experience, I have utilized agile methodologies to develop useful, intuitive, and performant web applications using modern technologies such as React/Rails. I have also built and enjoy building development tools that have solved several pain points in my team's development processes.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Oracle Oct 2022 – Present

## Software Developer 2

• Joined Oracle Health as part of their acquisition of Cerner Corporation

Cerner Corporation Jan 2016 – Oct 2022

# Software Engineer III

- Rebuilt a legacy solution as a modern responsive web app using HTML5, ES6, Ruby on Rails, and Java microservices
- Helped create the Modern Nursing Application to support many nursing workflows in a single solution. Involved creating many sub-apps that are embedded in other applications as well.
- Heavily used tools like webpack, babel, and ponyfills/polyfills to support and solve cross-browser compatibility issue.
- Implemented reusable, styled, internationalized, and accessible components with React
- Managed app state using Redux, Redux-Saga, and React context
- Heavily tested react components using testing frameworks like Enzyme, React Testing Library, and WebdriverIO
- Orchestrated efficient software deployments and package versioning to minimize client impact
- Built NodeJS scripts for automating the creation of reusable, themed, scalable icons from svg files
- Worked on nodejs and groovy scripts for automating the deployment process for multiple dependent node packages into a single Jenkins job
- Built a node package to help link requirements and tests together which is now being used by many other corporate teams
- Collaborated with several teams to contribute code fixes or features to many of Oracle Cerner's open-source packages
- Debugged code using the chrome debugger and the React, Redux, and Axe chrome extensions

# SmartCare Consultants May 2015 – Jan 2016

## Intern Software Programmer

- Gained internship experience in the healthcare startup culture
- Implemented CRUD actions for storing sensor data in php
- Continued work during the following semester to create a small mobile app as a proof of concept

### **Education/Awards**

**Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science –** Missouri University of Science and Technology **Innovate & Simplify Badge –** Cerner Corporation